Everyone wants to be found.
Lost in Translation is a drama, romance, comedy film directed by Sofia Coppola.
Two lost souls visiting Tokyo -- the young, neglected wife of a photographer and a washed-up movie star shooting a TV commercial
-- find an odd solace and pensive freedom to be real in each other's company, away from their lives in America.
Bob Harris, played by Bill Murray.
Charlotte, played by Scarlett Johansson.
John, played by Giovanni Ribisi.
Kelly, played by Anna Faris.
Ms. Kawasaki, played by Akiko Takeshita.
Press Agent, played by Kazuyoshi Minamimagoe.
Lost in Translation is a 2003 romantic comedy-drama film
written and directed by Sofia Coppola.
Bill Murray stars as Bob Harris, a fading American movie star who is having a
midlife crisis when he travels to Tokyo to promote Suntory whisky.
He befriends another disillusioned American, Charlotte (Scarlett
Johansson), a recent college graduate and married for two years.
Giovanni Ribisi, Anna Faris, and Fumihiro Hayashi are also featured.
The film explores themes of alienation and disconnection against
a backdrop of cultural displacement in Japan.
It does not use mainstream narrative conventions and is
atypical in its depiction of romance.
Coppola started writing the film after spending time in
Tokyo and becoming fond of the city.
She began forming a story about two characters experiencing a "romantic melancholy" in the Park Hyatt Tokyo,
where she stayed while promoting her first feature film, the 1999 drama The Virgin Suicides.
Coppola envisioned Murray playing the role of Bob from the
beginning and tried to recruit him for months.
While Murray eventually agreed to play the part, he did not sign a contract.
Coppola spent a quarter of the film's $4 million
budget without knowing if he would arrive.
Principal photography began on September 29, 2002, and lasted 27 days.
Coppola kept a flexible schedule during filming with
a small crew and minimal equipment.
The screenplay was short and Coppola allowed
significant improvisation during filming.
The director of photography, Lance Acord, used available light where possible, and many
Japanese places of business and public areas were used as locations.
After 10 weeks of editing, Coppola sold distribution rights for the United States and Canada
to Focus Features, and the company promoted the film through word of mouth.
Lost in Translation premiered on August 29, 2003, at the Telluride Film Festival,
and was distributed to American theatres on September 12, 2003.
It grossed $118 million worldwide and received acclaim for its writing, directing and
performances, though its depiction of Japan and Japanese people was criticized.
At the 76th Academy Awards, Lost in Translation won Coppola Best Original Screenplay, and the
film was nominated for Best Picture, Best Director and Best Actor (Murray).
Other accolades won include three BAFTAs and three Golden Globes.
It has since been named one of the greatest films of the 2000s and 21st century.
The film explores themes of hotel room, adultery,
japan, unsociability, upper class.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.